<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="../COML.xsl" type="text/xsl" media="screen" ?>
<?mso-infoPathSolution productVersion="11.0.8034" PIVersion="1.0.0.0" name="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:infopath:COML:http---www-vtc-vsc-edu-COML-0-0" language="en-us" href="COML.xsn" solutionVersion="1.0.0.47" ?>
<?mso-application progid="InfoPath.Document"?>

<outline created="2006-08-30" reviewed="2014-02-04" xmlns="http://www.vtc.vsc.edu/COML_0.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.vtc.vsc.edu/COML_0.0 ../COML.xsd">

  <summary>
    <authors>
      <author>Craig A. Damon</author>
    </authors>
    <department-program>Computer Information Systems</department-program>
    <number>CIS-1120</number>
    <title>Introduction to Information Science and Technology</title>
    <credits>3</credits>
    <graded>true</graded>
    <time lecture="3" laboratory="0" studio="0" recitation="0" study="6"/>
    <semesters>
      <semester>Fall</semester>
    </semesters>
    <description>This course introduces students to the world of IST across a broad range of
      topics. Topics include history of computing, computing in society, career paths in
      computing and the use of computers in the workplace.</description>
  </summary>
  
  <short-title>Intro to IST</short-title>
  <course-level>1000</course-level>
  
  <course-outcomes>
    <outcome>Understand the context of computing in the current society, including the business
      place.</outcome>
    <outcome>Understand the social consequences of modern computing technology and the way it
      is used.</outcome>
    <outcome>Understand the historical development of computing technology and its impact on
      current decisions.</outcome>
    <outcome>Make informed decisions about upcoming choices towards a computing major and
      technical electives.</outcome>
    <outcome>Understand the resources available to and expectations and responsibilities of a
      college student at Vermont Technical College.</outcome>
  </course-outcomes>
  
  <course-content>
    <summary>The details of the course may vary somewhat over time to stay topical and reflect
      current issues and interests. Typically, the bulk of the class will cover several broad
      themes. For each of these themes, the class should consider the historical, social,
      ethical, business and technological implications and development. In addition, the course
      will ensure that all students are exposed to key considerations of being a student at
      Vermont Technical College.</summary>
    
    <topic>Drivers of computing (modeling the natural world, counting and computing, and
      information management).</topic>
    <topic>Enabled technologies (telecommunication and networking, privacy and secrecy, media,
      optionally operations research).</topic>
    <topic>Foundations of computing (what is thinking, natural and artificial intelligence,
      robotics).</topic>
    <topic>Fun (gaming and graphics, the future).</topic>
    <topic>Resources available to students.</topic>
    <topic>Registration and other key processes.</topic>
    <topic>Word processing and related tools.</topic>
    <topic>Appropriate behavior in and out of classrooms.</topic>
  </course-content>
  
  <delivery-method>face-to-face</delivery-method>
  <evaluation>
    <method>Homework</method>
    <method>Quizzes</method>
    <method>Papers</method>
    <method>Final Exam</method>
  </evaluation>
  <additional-information>This course serves as a breadth first introduction to the field of
    computing for all IST students.</additional-information>
  
  <internal-comments>This course replaced HIS-1260, History of IT, which was a required first
    semester course for all IST students. As this course is taken by every first semester fall
    student, it incorporates the current Freshman Orientation material as
    well.</internal-comments>
</outline>
